
<!DOCTYPE BlogPosts [
<!ELEMENT BlogPosts (BlogPost)+>
<!ELEMENT BlogPost (date, topic, title, author, content, scripture, prayer?)>
<!ELEMENT date (#PCDATA)>
<!ELEMENT topic (#PCDATA)>
<!ELEMENT title (#PCDATA)>
<!ELEMENT author (#PCDATA)>
<!ELEMENT content (#PCDATA)>
<!ELEMENT scripture (#PCDATA)>
<!ELEMENT prayer (#PCDATA)>
]>
<BlogPosts>
    <BlogPost>
      <date> October 29, 2018</date>
      <topic>Prodigals</topic>
      <title>Warring for Prodigals</title>
      <author>Patricia van der Merwe</author>
      <content>Shaun, a 39-year-old prodigal was discovered at his home, lying in a drunken stupor, by his girlfriend. Blood flowed from his mouth, yet he refused to be taken to the hospital. His frail, jaundiced body bore little resemblance to the once handsome, vibrant young man. Doctors had warned him months earlier that if he did not quit drinking, he would die unnecessarily. Shaun did not or could not heed that warning.
With the girlfriend’s help he managed to stand to his feet. He staggered around the room only to fall again. Blood now began to gush from his mouth. As she knelt over Shaun, with trembling hands, the girl dialed 911 on her cell phone.
At the hospital, medical staff worked furiously to no avail. With all their state-of-the-art technology and frantic efforts, they were not able to halt the bleeding. Blood was now oozing from Shaun’s eyes and nose, and every possible opening in his body. His skin had turned a putrid shade of yellow. Nurses constantly changed his blood-soaked pillowcases.
At 4:00 AM family members were called to Shaun’s bedside. One by one they came to say good-bye, except for his nine-year-old daughter. The site of her father literally bleeding to death would have been too traumatic.
Within eight hours, Shaun was dead. If we could have lifted the curtain and peered into the spirit realm during that horrendous scene, we would probably have seen untold numbers of demons dancing gleefully as they awaited a victory for their side.
We would also have seen angels standing by waiting for someone to pray. Only then could they wield the sword of the Word and slay the enemy.
We read in Acts 12 that Herod had planned to afflict and torment some who belonged to the church. He succeeded in killing James the brother of John. When he found that pleased the Jews, he went further and arrested Peter with the intention of bringing him before the people after the Passover. But the church persisted in fervent prayer to God and an incredible thing happened.
As Peter slept, guarded and chained between two soldiers, an angel of the Lord showed up. He put the soldiers in a coma and woke Peter. He broke the chains, told Peter to get dressed and follow him. He led him to safety and immediately disappeared. Peter thought he was dreaming or having a vision.
That is what happens in the spirit realm when we pray for our prodigals. The chains fall off setting them free from their captives.
	Shaun was my nephew, but I was not at his bedside that horrible night. I can only say that I and others have prayed for family members for years. It is my belief that some little nurse or nurses’ aid, while changing Shaun’s blood-soaked bedding, would have told him about the life saving blood of Jesus Christ. That he, like the prodigal son in the Bible, went home to the Father. That being the case, the last scene behind that curtain would have been angels of God drawing their swords against the enemy. We would have seen the demons scatter, shrieking, “Foiled again.”
</content>
      <scripture>Acts 12</scripture>
      <prayer>prayer</prayer>
    </BlogPost>

   <BlogPost>
      <date>November 24, 2018</date>
      <topic>Generational Curses</topic>
      <title>What's in my Family Line?</title>
      <author>Katharine Gruber</author>
      <content>My fondest memories of my Grandpa, my mom’s dad, began around age four. That’s the year my family moved from Wisconsin back to Minnesota. I recently asked my Dad why we moved to Minnesota. Nothing prepared me for his response, for I hadn’t considered I could be the reason.
In the 1960’s, women’s treatment in the work place differed from men. My father, a math, chemistry, and physics teacher, taught High School in a small town in the middle of Wisconsin. When he accepted and signed his contract, there were no conditions or stipulations that he needed to work one year before he quit, moved or accepted a new job due to family.
Mom, on the other hand, was required to not get pregnant during her first-year of teaching. I have never signed a work contract that stipulated family planning as a condition for employment. That part of her contract was broken. I arrived that July between her first and second year of teaching.
My parents didn’t have family close by, so I was cared for by a family friend. At six-weeks old, I contracted my first childhood illness—chicken pox. Welcome to the benefits and liabilities of day care. Mom said I was the youngest case of chicken pox the doctor had ever treated. Other illnesses followed with increasing doctor bills and not having enough money to pay for them.
Grandpa
My dad found a teaching position located in a suburb south of St. Paul. He made enough money for my mom to quit teaching full-time and take care of me. I would be turning four that summer between school terms. They purchased their first new home that year, and to save money, they painted the inside of the house themselves. During their two weeks of painting, I lived with my mom’s parents.
I loved my mom’s parents. Grandma let me help make cookies, took me with her shopping, and introduced me to gardening. My grandpa wasn’t kind and sweet like my grandma. No, he’d walk around the corner of the living room singing little ditties, as he called them. His favorites were “Oh My Darlin’ Clementine” and another one about Phineas Fogg. He was loud, and kind of scary if I did something wrong. He’d raise his voice and yell “Yaaah,” assume a boxing stance and pretend to take a swipe, scaring and distracting me. I sensed his pent-up anger and began to walk on egg shells around him. Other times he was playful and would gently tweak my nose and pretend to pull it off, or reach behind my ear and open his hand to give me a quarter. That was a large sum of money for a four-year-old. He’d tell me not to spend it all in one place.
As I grew older, I noted why I felt scared around my grandpa. Every afternoon between lunch and supper, my grandfather indulged in gin and tonics. I noticed after his second or third drink, he’d say mean things, his eyes watered and looked bloodshot. Pity the unsuspecting person who dared to disagree with him on any topic. He’d raise his voice and verbally shut them down. I learned to keep my opinions to myself.
 When my great grandmother moved in with them, there’d be strong disagreements on politics. My grandmother did the best she could to restore peace but to little avail. Family dinners consisted of Grandpa’s verbal tirades then him succumbing to choking/coughing jags that ended the verbal battles. Everyone froze, waiting to see if he’d recover—he did.
Awareness
Mealtime cleanup created the perfect environment to learn the ins and outs of family members’ lives. Washing dishes wasn’t my favorite thing to do except during family get- togethers. After meals the men and boys walked outside or gathered in the living room to talk about cars, weather, and more politics. Topics I didn’t care about. The kitchen is where I learned about other relatives with drinking problems, who had been diagnosed with cancer or high blood pressure, which cousin had a baby out-of-wedlock, and so forth. I noticed there were patterns to certain illnesses and addictions that repeated through the generations. Would these patterns repeat in my life and those of my children? Could anything be done?
Discovery
Diseases, I thought, would be cured by scientific breakthroughs. The mantra I, along with my fellow laboratory students, stated, “When science cured the common cold, cancer will be a thing of the past.” We hoped that 10-years would be long enough. A couple of decades later, my hope rests elsewhere. How about the other things that run in family lines?
I admit that science has let me down. Medicine many times makes one comfortable and treats symptoms but not the disease’s root cause. It has its place but is only part of the solution. Through very difficult circumstances and nowhere to turn, I became a Christian. Guess what? My family line isn’t much different than those in the Bible. Within those families, there is murder, addiction, prostitution, famine, adultery and every other societal ill. Jesus also gives us the solution—prayer.
Hope
 I am now on the other side of parenting, that of watching my young-adult sons navigate adulthood, I see some of the negative patterns repeating and others have been avoided. The hardest thing about prayer is waiting and realizing it took generations for a pattern to be established, it may take longer than I want for the pattern to be replaced with something healthier. Until I see the results, I will keep praying and hanging onto hope.</content>
      <scripture>Exodus 20:5; Numbers 14:18; Deuteronomy 5:9-10;</scripture>
      <prayer>Dear Heavenly Father, I thank you that you sent your Son to die on the cross for me. In doing this, you freed me from the power of sin and death over my life. I renounce the curse of addiction that has traveled down my family line.
      I cancel its assignment over my family and thank you for your love and freedom. I plead the blood of Jesus over my generational line. In the name of Jesus I pray. Amen.</prayer>
    </BlogPost>
  </BlogPosts>
